# **David "Trent" Salazar**

949-324-6810 | dsal1951@gmail.com | TrentSalazar.com | 2020 Lawrence St. Apt 917, Denver CO 80205

### **SUMMARY**

Versatile Data Scientist and manager with demonstrated success building new teams and products in extremely fast-paced startup environments. Took over ownership of Datalogix's repository of past ad performance data – known as Norms – when it was still a manually populated spreadsheet. Over the next two years created the roadmap to develop and monetize Norms, evangelized the plan throughout the organization, and built a team of Data Scientists to execute it. Norms is now its own standalone product line, and is being integrated for use by analytics teams at some of the largest digital platforms such as Facebook, Pinterest, and Snapchat.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Oracle Denver, CO 2016-Current

Sr. Data Scientist

- Strategic Analytics Lead: Hired and managed a team of five direct reports, all Data Scientists with Masters or PhD, responsible for monetizing Oracle's experience in the digital measurement and targeting space through new product development and industry-facing research.
- New Product Development: Created a new product that provides advertisers with industry benchmarks and analysis to improve all dimensions of their digital advertising. The product utilizes a data visualization framework we developed in Python. Presented product prototype to senior marketing leaders at five of the largest consumer goods companies.
- **Industry Thought Leadership**: Defined thought leadership roadmap for Oracle Data Cloud. Led team of Data Scientists in the execution of the roadmap through original research and the delivery of industry-facing content such as conference presentations, whitepapers, op-ed pieces, infographics, blog posts, and sales collateral.

Oracle Denver, CO 2014-2015

Data Scientist

- **Business Development**: Quantified the incremental impact of Oracle's audience products on digital advertising performance. Presented findings to decision makers at Facebook and Twitter to help persuade them to allow Oracle audience products to be sold to advertisers through their platforms currently a nine-figure business for Oracle.
- **Predictive Modeling**: Led six-month research initiative to create a model that predicts which individuals would drive incremental sales in any digital advertising campaign. Utilized a number of tree-based machine learning techniques (using Scikit-learn and PySpark) to create models that were both predictive of future events and interpretable.
- **Web App Development**: Created an internal UI using AngularJS and D3 to provide teams throughout the company with secure access to all data and insights generated from Oracle's ROI<sup>TM</sup> measurement product.
- Promoted to Sr. Data Scientist after thirteen months while continuing to manage two Data Scientists.

Datalogix (acquired by Oracle) Denver, CO

2013-2014

Associate Data Scientist

- Client Consulting: Led custom research engagements for two of the largest social media platforms to analyze the performance of their targeting data and pricing algorithms. These projects generated over \$1.5MM of direct revenue for Datalogix and led to new business development opportunities with these partners.
- **Data Infrastructure**: Developed Datalogix's Norms database a repository of all advertising performance data collected on behalf of clients and created automated ETL processes to populate it using Python and SQL.
- Received first direct report after seven months and promoted to Data Scientist after ten months.

## J.P. Morgan New York, NY

2010

Investment Banking Summer Analyst

• Financial Modeling: Performed Discounted Cash Flow analysis and other valuation techniques as part of the IPO deal team for a large aerospace manufacturer looking to go public

### **EDUCATION**

Duke University Durham, NC

Graduated 2013

BS in Economics

Santa Margarita High School Trabuco Canyon, CA

Graduated 2008

International Baccalaureate Full Diploma

### **PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES**

Languages: Python (Pandas, Scikit-Learn, Matplotlib, StatsModels, Flask), R, JavaScript (AngularJS, D3js), SQL Tools: Amazon Web Services (Redshift, RDS, S3, EC2), IPython Notebook, Adobe Photoshop & Illustrator, MS Office, Tableau